Ben McAllister

Senior Software Developer



Summary

Agile developer with 5+ years of experience building solutions based on solid practices and robust designs. Currently in the point of sale industry managing codebases that deploy to 15,000+ POS terminals which process 80,000,000+ transactions per year. Background in architecture design, data structures, functional programming, parallel computing, and testing.

Experience

365 Retail Markets

Senior Mobile Developer

March 2024 - Present

- Performing Impact Analysis on upcoming projects to minimize time to delivery and technical debt.
- Working along side Product management to identify and solve customer issues.
- Managing multiple Git repositories, CI/CD pipelines, and code reviews for a team of 7.

Mobile Developer

Apr 2021 - March 2024

- Supported products like <u>PicoMarket/Cooler</u> and <u>365Pay</u> using Android and React-Native.
- Helped to design architecture for cross-company API interfaces using Retrofit.
- Oversaw production issues and triaging solutions for over 20% of the companies terminals.
- Integrated with multiple third party companies for payment processing in United States, Canada, United Kingdom, and European Union.
- Incorporated existing A.I. product recognition technology into PicoStockwell 2.0.
- Expanded basket calculation logic to handle value added tax rates for international sales.
- Refactored UI to simplify user flows, reduce code debt, and increase performance.

Junior Mobile Developer

Aug 2019 - Apr 2021

- Built software distribution system for timely terminal updates and status events. Reducing time to deployment and product downtime.
- Created products that integrate with external company technology like PicoCoolerBreeze.

Mobile Development Intern

May 2019 - Aug 2019

- Introduced self-setup software tools for Android POS terminals. Decreasing the cost, time to delivery, and complexity for new deployments.
- Updated Jest testing systems for React-Native application to improve code quality.

University of Michigan

Grader

Jun 2018 - May 2019

- Worked alongside professors in grading students in junior level computer science courses including Java Programming, Data Structures & Algorithm Analysis, and x86 Assembly.

Education

University of Michigan - Dearborn

Sep 2017 - Dec 2019

Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering.

Oakland Community College

Sep 2014 - May 2017

Associate in Applied Science degrees in Software Engineering and Technological Sciences.

Skills & Tools

- Agile Development - Google Firebase - React

- Algorithm Analysis - Gradle - React-Native - AWS - HTML - Retrofit

- Azure DevOps - Intellij - Rust

- C# - Jest - Spring Boot (Kotlin/Java) - C++ - Kotlin/Java - SQL (MySQL/SQLite)

- Codacy - LATEX - Tailwind

- CSS - Linux - TypeScript/JavaScript

Deno
Express (Node.js)
Native Android/iOS
VSCode
x86 Assembly

- Git - Python

Additional Projects

- Flow Solver: Rust Algorithm to solve Flow Free games in seconds using backtracking.
- **GPU Crawler**: Custom Rust web scraper to periodically check for Graphics Cards during the shortage of 2021.
- Advent of Code Solutions: Public repository with Rust solutions to Advent of Code.
- Minesweeper AI: Algorithm that uses linear algebra to solve minesweeper (Java).
- C++ Code Smell Visualization: Script that identifies unsound C++ code (Python).
- <u>Dungeon Board</u>: Standalone application for board games that displays on another screen with fog of war and multiple image layers (Java).
- **PushPoint**: App that serves ads using geofencing (Android/Firebase/Java/JavaScript).